Charles Sheeler
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Printed Material, 1923-1966, Series 5:; (Boxes 2-4, 7; 1.5 linear feet)
  - Books, 1945-1963, 5.4:
    - Sight and Insight, 1956, (by Alexander Eliot) (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - The Great King...King of Assyria, Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1946, (2 copies) (Box 7 (sol), Folder 1-2)
  - Journals and Magazines, 1923-1966, 5.5:
    - The Arts, 1923 May, (See Box 7) (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Life Magazine, 1938 August, (See Box 7) (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Fortune Magazine, 1939 April, (See Box 7) (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Fortune Magazine, 1940 December, (See Box 7) (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - "Power: Six Paintings by Charles Sheeler," Fortune Magazine, 1940 December, (See Box 7) (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Pageant, 1947 June (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Reader's Digest, 1951 February (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Art in America, 1954 October (Box 3 (hol), Folder 1)
    - Art in America, 1955 October (Box 3 (hol), Folder 2)
    - Art News, 1955 Summer (Box 3 (hol), Folder 3)
    - Aperture, 1956 Vol. 4 No. 3 (Box 3 (hol), Folder 4)
    - Art in America, 1956 Spring (Box 3 (hol), Folder 5)
    - American Artist, 1959 January (Box 3 (hol), Folder 6)
    - Art in America, 1960 No. 3 (Box 3 (hol), Folder 7)
    - Art in America, 1965 No. 1 (Box 3 (hol), Folder 8)
    - Journal of the Archives of American Art, 1965 April (Box 3 (hol), Folder 9)
    - New Hampshire Profiles, 1966 May (Box 3 (hol), Folder 10)
    - Life Magazine, 1938 August (Box 7 (sol), Folder 3)
    - Fortune Magazine, 1939 April (Box 7 (sol), Folder 4)
    - Fortune Magazine, 1940 December (Box 7 (sol), Folder 5)
    - "Power: Six Paintings by Charles Sheeler," Fortune Magazine, 1940 December (Box 7 (sol), Folder 6)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1931-1966, 5.6:
    - Clippings, 1931, 1938 (Box 3 (hol), Folder 11)
    - Clippings, 1947, 1953-1954 (Box 3 (hol), Folder 12)
    - Clippings, 1955-1958 (Box 3 (hol), Folder 13)
    - Clippings, 1959 (Box 3 (hol), Folder 14)
    - Clippings, 1960-1962 (Box 3 (hol), Folder 15)
    - Clippings, 1963 (Box 3 (hol), Folder 16)
    - Clippings, 1965-1966 (Box 3 (hol), Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1959-1965, 5.7:
    - Eugene Meyer Eulogy, 1959 (Box 4 (hol), Folder 1)
    - John Fitzgerald Kennedy Presidential Inaugural Invitation, 1961 (Box 4 (hol), Folder 2)
    - America: The Artists Eye, 1963, (publicity packet) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 3)
    - Unused Appointment Calendar, 1963 (Box 4 (hol), Folder 4)
    - Rockefeller Memorial Windows Brochure, circa 1965 (Box 4 (hol), Folder 5)
- Photographs, circa 1840s-1963, Series 6:; (Box 4, OV11; 0.4 linear feet)
  Photographs date from circa 1840s-1963 and include photographs of Sheeler's family, of Sheeler, and of Sheeler with friends and colleagues. There is one daguerreotype and two ambrotypes of unidentified women (possibly Sheeler's relatives) and of a young child (possibly Sheeler). Two tintypes depict unidentified woman and Charles Sheeler as a child. There are copyprints of these originals.
  Additional photographs are of Sheeler's mother and father (or possibly Sheeler's grandparents), of Sheeler, of Sheeler with his wife Musya, Sheeler with William Lane, Sheeler with Edward Weston, and Sheeler with Edward Steichen and John Marin. The series also includes photographs of Sheeler's collection of Shaker furniture, and photographs of exhibitions.
  Items are arranged by subject and date.
  - Unidentified Women (possibly Sheeler's relatives), circa 1840s-1880s (Box 4 (hol), Folder 6)
  - Sheeler Parents or Grandparents, circa 1880s-1900s (Box 4 (hol), Folder 7)
  - Sheeler's Boyhood Home, circa 1800s-1910s (Box 4 (hol), Folder 8)
  - Charles Sheeler, circa 1883-1958 (Box 4 (hol), Folder 9)
  - Sheeler with Wife Musya, 1947, 1961 (Box 4 (hol), Folder 10)
  - Unidentified Friends, circa 1950s (Box 4 (hol), Folder 11)
  - Sheeler with Edward Weston, 1954, (photographs by George Waters) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 12)
  - Sheeler with William Lane, 1958, (photographs by Musya Sheeler) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 13)
  - Sheeler with Edward Steichen and John Marin1958, (see OV11) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 14)
  - Sheeler with Others, 1961 (Box 4 (hol), Folder 15)
  - Sheeler's Shaker Furniture Collection, 1962, (photographed by the Philadelphia Museum of art for the exhibit The Shakers: Their Arts and Crafts) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 16)
  - Exhibition Photographs, The Shakers: Their Arts and Crafts, 1962, (exhibited at the Philadelphia Museum of Art) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 17)
  - Photographs of a Sheeler Exhibition, circa 1963, (possibly a retrospective) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 18)
  - Sheeler with Edward Steichen and John Marin, 1958, (three photographs) (Box OV 11)
  - Unidentified Older Woman, circa 1840s-1880s, (daguerreotype) (Box Photo Drawer 8)
  - Unidentified Woman, circa 1840s-1880s, (ambrotype) (Box Photo Drawer 8)
  - Unidentified Woman, circa 1840s-1880s, (ambrotype) (Box Photo Drawer 8)
  - Unidentified Woman, circa 1840s-1880s, (tintype) (Box Photo Drawer 8)
  - Young Child (possibly Charles Sheeler), circa 1884, (ambrotype) (Box Photo Drawer 8)
  - Charles Sheeler as a Boy, circa 1886, (tintype) (Box Photo Drawer 8)
- Artwork, circa 1930s-1960s, Series 7:; (Boxes 4-5, 8-9, OV12-OV14; 1.1 linear feet)
  The artwork series consists of art works by Sheeler and others, which date from circa 1930s-1960. The series is particularly rich documenting Sheeler's industrial designs, fabrics and manufactured objects. Artwork by Sheeler includes oversize sketches, industrial designs, fabrics and manufactured objects. The series also includes a drawing by Peggy Bacon (a gift for Sheeler's birthday), and an art photograph by Minor White. There is also a copy negative and copy print for this photograph.
  The industrial designs are dated circa early 1930s, and were possibly commissioned by Samuel M. Kootz Associates. They include designs for a flower pot stand, cream and sugar set, sandwich tray, smoking stand, and a wood rack. The fabrics are in a variety of types and patterns including, knitted wool, linen, and printed rayon (or silk). The objects include a glass tumbler manufactured by the Steuben Glass Company, and a salt and pepper shaker set and silver tea spoon, both possibly manufactured by Revere Copper and Brass Inc. The fabrics and manufactured objects were exhibited at the Downtown Gallery's Practical Manifestations in Art, in December 1934.
  A copy negative and copy print have been created for Minor White's photograph, which are filed with the original.
  The series is arranged into two subseries:
  Subseries 7.1: Artwork by Sheeler, circa 1930s-1960s
  Subseries 7.2: Artwork by Others, circa 1940s-1960s
  - Artwork by Sheeler, circa 1930s-1960s, 7.1:
    - Industrial Designs, circa 1930s, (See OV 12-OV 13) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 19)
    - Glass Tumbler, circa 1934, (See Box 5) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 20)
    - Salt and Pepper Shaker Set, circa 1934, (See Box 5) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 21)
    - Silver Tea Spoon, circa 1934, (See Box 5) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 22)
    - Fabrics, circa 1934, (See Boxes 8-9) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 23)
    - Pen and Ink Sketch (probably by Sheeler), circa 1940s-1960s (Box 4 (hol), Folder 24)
    - Sketches, circa 1950s-1960s, (See OV14) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 25)
    - Glass Tumbler, circa 1934 (Box 5 (hol), Folder 5)
    - Salt and Pepper Shaker Set, circa 1934 (Box 5 (hol), Folder 6)
    - Silver Tea Spoon, circa 1934 (Box 5 (hol), Folder 7)
    - Fabrics, circa 1934-1936 (Box 8 (sol))
    - Fabrics, circa 1934-1936 (Box 9 (sol))
    - Design for a Flower Pot Stand, circa 1930s (Box OV 12)
    - Design for a Cream and Sugar Set, circa 1930s (Box OV 13)
    - Design for a Sandwich Tray, circa 1930s (Box OV 13)
    - Design for a Smoking Stand, circa 1930s (Box OV 13)
    - Design for a Wood Rack, circa 1930s (Box OV 13)
    - Sketches, circa 1950s-1960s (Box OV 14)
  - Artwork by Others, circa 1930s-1960s, 7.2:
    - Drawing by Peggy Bacon, circa 1940s-1960s (Box 4 (hol), Folder 26)
    - Photograph by Minor White, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 4 (hol), Folder 27)